let questions = [
        {
          numb: 1,
          question: "What does PHP stand for?",
          answer: "A. Both (i) and (ii)",
          options: [
            "i) Personal Home Page",
            "ii) Hypertext Preprocessor",
            "iii) Pretext Hypertext Processor",
            "iv) Preprocessor Home Page"
          ]
        },
        {
          numb: 2,
          question: "Who is the father of PHP?",
          answer: "A. Rasmus Lerdorf",
          options: [
            "A. Rasmus Lerdorf",
            "B. Willam Makepiece",
            "C. Drek Kolkevi",
            "D. List Barely"
          ]
        },
        {
          numb: 3,
          question: "PHP files have a default file extension of?",
          answer: "C. .php",
          options: [
            "A. .html",
            "B. .xml",
            "C. .php",
            "D. .ph"
          ]
        },
        {
          numb: 4,
          question: "A PHP script should start with ___ and end with ___:",
          answer: "D. < ?php ? >",
          options: [
            "A. < php >",
            "B. < ? php ?>",
            "C. < ? ? >",
            "D. < ?php ? >"
          ]
        },
        {
          numb: 5,
          question: "Which of the looping statements is/are supported by PHP?",
          answer: "C. All of the mentioned",
          options: [
            "i) for loop",
            "ii) while loop",
            "iii) do-while loop",
            "iv) foreach loop"
          ]
        },
        {
          numb: 6,
          question: "Which of the following is/are a PHP code editor?",
          answer: "B. All of the mentioned.",
          options: [
            "i) Notepad",
            "ii) Notepad++",
            "iii) Adobe Dreamweaver",
            "iv) PDT"
          ]
        },
        {
          numb: 7,
          question: "Which of the following must be installed on your computer so as to run PHP script?",
          answer: "D. (ii), (iii) and (iv)",
          options: [
            "i) Adobe Dreamweaver",
            "ii) PHP",
            "iii) Apache",
            "iv) IIS"
          ]
        },
        {
          numb: 8,
          question: "We can use ___ to comment a single line?",
          answer: "C. (ii), (iii) and (iv)",
          options: [
            "i) /?",
            "ii) //",
            "iii) #",
            "iv) /* */"
          ]
        },
        {
          numb: 9,
          question: "Which of the below symbols is a newline character?",
          answer: "B. \n",
          options: [
            "A. \\r",
            "B. \\n",
            "C. /n",
            "D. /r"
          ]
        },
        {
          numb: 10,
          question: "Which of the following php statement/statements will store 111 in variable num?",
          answer: "C. Only (iii)",
          options: [
            "i) int $num = 111;",
            "ii) int mum = 111;",
            "iii) $num = 111;",
            "iv) 111 = $num;"
          ]
        },
        {
          numb: 11,
          question: "Which of following variables can be assigned a value to it?",
          answer: "D. (ii) and (iv)",
          options: [
            "(i) $3hello",
            "(ii) $_hello",
            "(iii) $this",
            "(iv) $This"
          ]
        },
        {
          numb: 12,
          question: "PHP’s numerically indexed array begin with position __.",
          answer: "C. 0",
          options: [
            "A. 1",
            "B. 2",
            "C. 0",
            "D. -1"
          ]
        },
        {
          numb: 13,
          question: "Which of the functions is used to sort an array in descending order?",
          answer: "C. rsort()",
          options: [
            "A. sort()",
            "B. asort()",
            "C. rsort()",
            "D. dsort()"
          ]
        },
        {
          numb: 14,
          question: "Which of the following are correct ways of creating an array?",
          answer: "A. (iii) and (iv)",
          options: [
            "(i) state[0] = “karnataka”;",
            "(ii) $state[] = array(“karnataka”);",
            "(iii) $state[0] = “karnataka”;",
            "(iv) $state = array(“karnataka”);"
          ]
        },
      
        {
          numb: 15,
          question: "Which of the following multithreaded servers allow PHP as a plug-in?",
          answer: "d. All of the above",
          options: [
            "a. Netscape FastTrack",
            "b. Microsoft’s Internet Information Server",
            "c. O’Reilly’s WebSite Pro",
            "d. All of the above"
          ]
        },
        {
          numb: 16,
          question: "Which of the following type cast is not correct?",
          answer: "c. decimal",
          options: [
            "a. real",
            "b. double",
            "c. decimal",
            "d. boolean"
          ]
        },
        {
          numb: 17,
          question: "Which of the following are the valid PHP data types?",
          answer: "d. All of the above",
          options: [
            "a. resource",
            "b. null",
            "c. boolean",
            "d. All of the above"
          ]
        },
        {
          numb: 18,
          question: "Which of the following functions output text?",
          answer: "c. both a,b",
          options: [
            "a. echo()",
            "b. print()",
            "c. both a,b",
            "d. display()"
          ]
        },
        {
          numb: 19,
          question: "Which of the following statement is not correct for PHP?",
          answer: "c. It can run on windows and Linux systems only",
          options: [
            "a. It is a server side scripting language",
            "b. A PHP file may contain text, html tags or scripts",
            "c. It can run on windows and Linux systems only",
            "d. It is compatible with most of the common servers used today"
          ]
        },
        {
          numb: 20,
          question: "Which of the following printing construct/function accepts multiple parameters?",
          answer: "a. echo",
          options: [
            "a. echo",
            "b. print",
            "c. printf",
            "d. All of the above"
          ]
        },
        {
          numb: 40,
          question: "What will be the output of the following code?\n$a = 10;\nif ($a > 5 OR < 15)\necho ‘true’;\nelse\necho ‘false’;",
          answer: "d. Parse Error",
          options: [
            "a. true",
            "b. false",
            "c. No output",
            "d. Parse Error"
          ]
        }
      ];        